# 狗
Doggy!
# 你看 上次帶下來的小狗
Look! This is one of the doggies that we brought here last time.
# 現在那麼大啦
He's already that big now,
# 現在變黃啦
and has turned brown.
# 以前都是灰色的 嗯 現在都變黃色啦
He used to be grey. Um, but now he has turned brown.
# 戴著口罩 我戴著口罩它不認識我
With the mask, he can't recognize me as I'm wearing the mask.
# 叫它它不過來
He doesn't come even when I call him.
# 是不是
Am I right?
# 叫你你不過來啊
You were ignoring my call.
# 是啊 過來
Yes, you are. Come here!
# 不(用)[SIC]可以這樣子的
C'mon! It's not nice!
# 你看 給點草給你吃要不要
Look! Shall I give you some grass?
# 這草很好吃的哦
The grass is really tasty!
# 打滾啊
He's rolling.
# 啊
Ah!
# 賴皮 耍賴了哈
He's begging my attention, shamelessly, ha!
# 你妹妹呢
Where is your sister?
# 狗
Doggy!
# 狗 來啦 來啦
Doggy! She's coming, she's coming!
# 它妹妹
His sister
# 我戴著口罩它不認識我啊
She can't recognize me as I'm wearing the mask.
# 你看 它們兩個又要打架
Look! They're starting a fight again.
# 過來
Come here!
# 小狗
Doggies!
# 過來
Come here!
# 干架啦
So they start fighting.
# 太調皮啦 它們兩個
These two kids are simply too naughty!
# 你看 兄弟的貓 現在都好胖啦
Look! My buddy's cat, is already that fat now.
# 喵
Meow!
# 我不去 一去到它就跑啦
I'll leave it alone. It will run away if I get any closer.
# 這個貓差不多五六斤哦 那麼大
This cat is almost three kilograms, so big.
# 喵
Meow!
# 老是在叫 不知道叫甚麼
It's always yelping, but who knows why.
# 喵
Meow!
# 摸一摸你
Let me touch you.
# 喵
Meow!
# 摸都不要我摸 跑啦
No, it doesn't allow. It runs away.
# 喵
Meow!
# 過來
Come here!
# 握個手
Shake hand with me!
# 跑啦
It runs away,
# 不要我摸
from my touch.
# 大家好 今天天氣很不錯哦
Hi everyone! The weather today is really not bad.
# 我們上山挖點那個竹笋下來吃
Let's go onto the hill and get some, you know, some bamboo shoots.
# 就在這上面一點
It's just a bit up there.
# 從這裡上去
Let's go up from here.
# 挖了一天 一個竹笋都沒挖到
I've been digging for a whole day. But not even a single bamboo shoot is found.
# 你看 這個大葉蘭 這個蘭花(註︰找不到一個合理的「大葉蘭」翻譯，大葉蘭是人民幣上的水印，有人知道英文是甚麼嗎？)
Look! This is "Da Yelan" (Lit: big leave orchid, a local plant), it's orchid.
# 挖回去 自己種
Let me dig it out, and plant it at my place.
# 這個很靚的哦 這個
It's really beautiful, this orchid.
# 竹笋沒挖到
No bamboo shoots.
# 總不能空著手回去吧
But getting back home empty-handed is not an option.
# 你看 是不是很靚的
Look! Isn't it beautiful?
# 這個蘭花
This orchid
# 我拿回去自己種
I'll plant it at my place.
# 收工收工收工
Go, go, go!
# 好啦 回去啦
Alright! Let's go back.
# 路又好遠啊 我們走了好遠
It's a long way. We've gone far far away.
# 有一個這個過山車坐一下就好啦 (註︰他這個「過山車」應該是指走在山去的四驅車之類的吧)
I wish I had a mountain truck.
# 沒有
But I don't have.
# 啊 慢慢走回去吧
Ah! Let's go on foot, slowly.
# 挖個坑來
Let me dig a pit,
# 把這個蘭花種下來
and plant the orchid here,
# 種在這院子裡面
plant it in this yard.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
The video ends here.
# 你看 很靚的哦
Look! It's really beautiful!